Paetel, Karl O.; Papers ger072
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Karl O. Paetel Papers
1904-1984
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ger072
70 cubic ft.
Karl Otto Paetel was a political journalist, born in Berlin, forced to flee Germany in 1935 (Paetel was sentenced to death in absentia by the Nazis), and immigrated to the United States in 1940. Paetel's interests focused on the radical movements and social changes in the Twentieth Century from his youth until his death in 1975. The collection consists of correspondence, Paetel's writings, writings by others, pamphlets, biographical materials, and periodicals.
Biographical History
Karl Otto Paetel was born on November 23, 1906 in Berlin, where he attended school from the elementary levels through university studies at the Friedrich-Wilhelm University of Berlin. It was during his time at the Siemens-Oberrealschule (1923-27) that Paetel first became a member of a youth group, the Kngener Bund; he later joined the group Deutsche Freischar. His early association with youth groups and the German Youth Movement (Jugendbewegung) remained one of the major interests throughout his lifetime. The German Youth Movement became popular shortly after World War I and had a major influence on that generation of German intellectuals who grew up in the first third of the Twentieth Century. Paetel became a leader of the movement and, at the age of twenty-four, co-edited with Ernst Jünger, Die Kommenden, a central periodical of the movement.
In 1930 Paetel was arrested as a participant in an anti-Versailles demonstration by Berlin students, an event which led to the loss of his stipendium for university study, the discontinuation of his studies and his turn to journalism full-time. In addition to his work on Die Kommenden, Paetel also became editor of the Handbuch der deutschen Jugendbewegung, as well as the periodicals, Die sozialistische Nation and Antifaschistische Briefe. In 1932, he also became leader of the radical group, Gruppe sozialrevolutionrer Nationalisten. His activities led to his arrest and internment on several occasions during the years 1933-1934.
In January of 1935, Paetel was forced to flee Germany to Czechoslovakia where he remained for six months, continuing to write for such periodicals as Die neue Weltbhne and Neues Tagebuch. During the period from July 1935 to March 1937, Paetel went to Sweden via Denmark, then back to Czechoslovakia, to Austria, Switzerland, Belgium, and finally to France. Paetel spent nearly three years in France where he continued to write and eventually edited and published a series of underground pamphlets for German youth entitled Schriften der Jungen Nation.
After being officially deprived of his German citizenship and sentenced to death in absentia in 1939, Paetel was next interned in Roland Gaross-Damigny-Bassance, a French prisoner-of-war camp (February-June 1940). After his release from the camp, he fled through France to Lisbon, Portugal, and sailed in December 1940 to the United States.
Paetel arrived in New York City on January 13, 1941. Over the next several years, he held positions for the Office of European Economic Research and the Army Service Force, Morale Services Division of the War Department. He also performed research tasks for other writers, American institutes and agencies and continued to write on his own. His publications during these years included Nazi-Deutsch: A Glossary of Contemporary German Usage (with Heinz Paechter, Bertha Hellman, Hedwig Paechter, 1944), Ernst Jünger: Die Wandlung eines deutschen Dichters und Patrioten (1946), Deutsche innere Emigration: Anti-Nationalsozialistische Zeugnisse aus Deutschland (1946), Ernst Jünger: Weg und Wirkung: Eine Erfllung (1949), and Ernst Jünger: Eine Bibliographie (1953).
Paetel's interest in the radical movements of the day continued throughout his lifetime and is reflected in his writings. These movements included National Bolshevism (Nationalbolschewismus), a movement describing a group of individuals who were nationalists in the political sense, but socialists in economic terms; in 1965 Paetel published a history of National Bolshevism in German entitled Versuchung oder Chance? His interest in individuals, who did not fit into neat political or social categories, led to his interest in the American Beat movement and especially writer, Jack Kerouac, a leading beat poet; Paetels Beat Anthologie (1962) is one of the earliest publications on the American Beat Generation. Another prominent interest in his life, especially after 1933 and his escape from Nazi Germany, was German resistance to National Socialism (Widerstand) and exile. Das Dritte Reich und seine Gegner is only one example of his many writings on the topic of resistance.
Chronology of Events
1906 23 November, Born in Berlin, Germany
1913-1917 Attended Volksschule (elementary school).
1917-1923 Attended Hindenburg-Realschule.
1923-1927 Attended Siemens-Oberrealschule, Berlin
Became a member of the youth group Köngener Bund
Became a member of the youth group Deutscher Freischar
1926-1927 Worked free-lance, then as a city editor for the Deutsche Tageblatt.
1928-1929 Attended Deutsche Hochschule für Politik, Berlin.
1928-1930 Studied history, philosophy and German literature at the Friedrich-Wilhelm-Universität of Berlin.
1929-1930 Performed duties of editor-in-chief of Das junge Volk, non-partisan organ of the German youth group Bündische Jugend.
1928-1933 Editor of the monthly newsletter Politische Zeitschriftenschau (review of political magazines of all parties).
1930 Arrested as participant in an Anti-Versailles-Demonstration by Berlin students; subsequent loss of his stipendium for study; discontinuation of studies and turned to journalism full-time.
30 March 1930 Expelled from the youth group Deutsche Freischar because of an article he wrote entitled, "Absage an Hindenburg." Formed alliance with the followers of Otto Strasser.
1930 Editor of the weekly Die Kommenden; also editor of the Handbuch der deutschen Jugendbewegung.
1931-1933 Editor of Die sozialistische Nation, until it was condemned in 1933.
1932 Editor of the newsletter Antifaschistische Briefe, featuring anti-Nazi material for newspapers. Became leader of the group, Gruppe sozialrevolutionärer Nationalisten.
1933-1934 Arrested in Germany and interned on several occasions
1935 28 January-16 July, Fled Germany to Czechoslovakia, where he remained for six months, contributing to German exile publications such as Die neue Weltbühne, Neues Tagebuch, etc.
1935-1936 Went to Sweden, via Denmark; in Stockholm from 8 October 1935 – 8 October 1936; attended Birkagarden College in Stockholm.
1936 9 October Arrested in Stockholm; detained for 3 days
15 October 1936-March 1937 Return to Czechoslovakia for three months, then via Austria, Switzerland, Belgium to France.
March 1937- August 1940 Received visa for France, where he lived for three years, mostly in Paris; edited and published a series of underground pamphlets for German youth, Schriften der Jungen Nation
13 April 1939 Deprived of German citizenship (Reichsanzeiger); sentenced to death (by hanging) in Germany in absentia
8 February-21 June 1940 Interned in French prisoner of war camp, Roland Gaross-Damigny-Bassance
22 June - December 1940 Flight through France with false Czech papers; spent several months in Lisbon, Portugal; arrested and interned for several days in Spain; emigrated to the United States
13 Jan. 1941 Arrived in New York on the Serpa Pinto
1941-1949 Performed free-lance research work for American and European authors (incl. Vicki Baum for her novel Weeping Wood), Stanford Griffith, also for American institutes and agencies.
22 July 1942-20 Sept. 1943 Staff member of the Office of European Economic Research (OEER), affiliated with the OSS.
1942 Married Elisabeth Zerner
Summer 1944-Summer 1945 Fellowship of the Institute of International Education through the Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars; grant from the American Committee for Refugee Scholars, Writers and Artists, Inc.
Fall 1944-Jan. 1945 Consultant in the German language section of the Army Service Forces (War Dept.), Morale Services Division
1947-1948 Publisher and editor of German newsletter, Deutsche Gegenwart, a digest from German newspapers, periodicals, and excerpts from German letters and articles.
1947-1948 Teacher of German at the Barbizon Language School, 213 West 71st St., New York
1948 Teacher of German at the Automen Language School, 4 East 43rd St., New York
April-June 1949 Returned to Germany for a 10-week lecture tour, and to visit his dying father.
1956 Honored with a citation from the Süddeutsche Rundfunk.
Sept. 1959 Formation of Deutschsprachiges Forum
7 December 1967 Awarded the Bundesverdienstkreuz 1. Klasse der Bundesrepublik Deutschland
4 May 1975 Died, after a long illness, in Forest Hills, New York
19 May 1975 Memorial service at the Goethe House, 1014 Fifth Avenue, New York, NY.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains autobiographical materials, diary, 1940, correspondence with Hannah Arendt, Manfred George, Ernst Junger, Henry Kissinger, Reinhold Niebuhr, Paul Tillich, and others, 1940-1972, manuscripts of books, articles, essays, and reviews, 1940-1972, offprints and clippings, materials pertaining to five exile magazines published by Paetel, four audio recordings, 1957-1966, and photographs. The collection also includes a large collection of ephemera pertaining to the German Youth Movement, anti-Nazi resistance, refugee problems, exile writers, and postwar German politics. Paetel also retained manuscripts of and biographical materials pertaining to the German novelist Ernst Jünger and the manuscript and woodcuts for a children's book by Käte Döring.
The Karl O. Paetel Papers consist of 71.5 linear ft. of materials, which reflect its owner's many interests including Jugendbewegung (the German Youth Movement), Widerstand (resistance to Hitler), writer Ernst Junger, refugees and exile topics. Although his main collection of materials pertaining to the Jugendbewegung was bequeathed to the Archiv der deutschen Jugendbewegung in Burg Ludwigstein, Germany, duplicate materials pertaining to the youth movement, as well as the remainder of his collection, is located in Albany. Paetel was an avid collector of books, pamphlets, periodicals and other materials on the subjects of his interest, many of which have been retained in his collection.
The correspondence section, dating primarily from 1940-1975, contains many original letters as well as photocopies of many original letters which were transferred to Burg Ludwigstein.
The manuscript section contains manuscripts of both Paetel's published and unpublished writings. Included are manuscripts of several of his major published works, numerous essayistic pieces, as well as several volumes in planning stages. The publications section contains originals (many as clippings) and copies of Paetel's publications, including a nearly complete set of his essayistic writings and numerous reviews in newspapers, periodicals and books.
In his capacity as editor of several periodicals, including Deutsche Blätter, Deutsche Gegenwart and Gesprchsfetzen, Paetel received manuscripts from other writers. The section containing manuscripts by others includes shorter manuscripts by such authors as Paul Amann, Heinz Gollong, Alfred Gong, Paul Hagen, Werner Kindt, Th. Kögler and Robert Koehl and longer manuscripts by Michael Wurmbrand and Frederic McLean.
Of significant interest in the collection are Paetel's collections of materials on various topics, including sizable collections on Ernst Jünger, Heinz Gollong, Widerstand and Jugendbewegung. The various topics are supplemented by the additional materials, which are located in both the pamphlet and the periodicals collections.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into nine topical series with further subseries.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Elizabeth (Mrs. Karl) Paetel in May 1980.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Military and Armed Conflict; Literature; Politics and Politicians; Social Activists and Public Advocates; Exiles' writings, German.; Germany--Emigration and immigration; Journalism--Political aspects; Youths' periodicals, German; Junger, Ernst, 1895-1998.
- Biographical Files, Documents, 1907-1975; 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains numerous articles about Paetel or in which he is mentioned, dating from 1930-1982 and including a number of obituaries and memorial addresses (1975). Also included in this section are materials pertaining to the two Festschrifts published on the occasions of his 50th (Aufrecht zwischen den Sthlen) and his 65th (Don Quichotte en miniature) birthdays. Documents include several pertaining to Paetel's parents and grandparents, documents pertaining to emigration, numerous job applications and accompanying recommendation letters, as well as Wiedergutmachung (restitution) documents. In addition, the series includes numerous address lists (mailing lists for publications, periodicals) and membership lists.
  - General articles about Paetel or in which Paetel is mentioned Original and pc. 35 items., 1930-1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General articles about Paetel or in which Paetel is mentioned Original and pc. 51 items., 1953-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Series of articles from the BZ am Mittag, "Die deutsche Jugend ringt mit der Zukunft," in which Paetel is featured, 1932 October 20-1932 November 24; 1932 November 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lexicon entries and questionnaires for lexicon entries, incl. Wer ist wer?, Kürschners Deutscher Literatur-Kalendar., Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Biographical statements written for book jackets, publicity statements, etc., Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Unpublished biographical statements (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Documents pertaining to Paetel's parents, grandparents (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Baptismal certificate, 1907 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Press cards, identification cards, 1932-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Recommendation letters for Paetel 61 items, 1933-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Recommendation letters, transcripts and copies, 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Safe conduct papers, France, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Curriculum vita, 1940-1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Haft und Exilzeit." Notes concerning Paetel's exile and emigration years, 1941-1959 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - U.S. Selective Service, draft and appeal documents, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Die Deutsche Jugendfront." Report of the German Geheime Staatspolizei (Gestapo), Berlin, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Job applications, application letters, 1942-1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Deutsche Blätter. Registration forms, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Announcements of lectures by Paetel, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Visit to Germany, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Tagebuchblätter Juli. Ein Besuch nach Deutschland." 5 x 7 black notebook containing daily entries., 1949 April 1-1949 April 20 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letters concerning naturalization and citizenship, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Publisher's contract (Otto H.F. Meyer), ca.1950 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Paetel's book donations, Deutsches Institut für Geschichte der Nationalsozialistischen Zeit, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Wiedergutmachung / Restitution. Application, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Wiedergutmachung / Restitution. Letters and documentation, 1952-1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Wiedergutmachung / Restitution. Income statements, 1941-1959 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Wiedergutmachung / Restitution. Letters and documentation, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Articles on the occasion of Paetel's 50 th birthday; reviews of Festschrift written on the occasion of his 50th birthday, Aufrecht zwischen den Stühlen., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Aufrecht zwischen den Stühlen – incomplete copy, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Aufrecht zwischen den Stühlen. Scrapbook copy with congratulatory letters, souvenirs, etc. pasted in., Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Aufrecht zwischen den Stühlen. Copies of congratulatory letters from scrapbook., Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Articles on the occasion of Paetel's 60 th birthday, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Materials concerning Don Quichotte en miniature, in honor of Paetel's 65th birthday, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Don Quichotte en miniature. Manuscript version, Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Don Quichotte en miniature. Grüße zum 65. Geburtstag am für Karl O. Paetel von Freunden in Deutschland und anderswo. 3 copies., 1971 November 23 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 50 th birthday, congratulatory letters, 1971 November (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Bundesverdienstkreuz Klasse, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Open letters (Rundbriefe, Krankenberichte), 1951-1990 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Last will and testament, Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Book donations, C. W. Post, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Death certificate, funeral arrangements, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Excerpts from condolence letters, obituaries, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Obituaries, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Memorial celebration: "Rundbrief über die Gedenkfeier für KOP.", Undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Partial transcript of an interview with Paetel, Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Krapp, Fritz. "Karl Otto Paetel. Versuch eines Porträts. T. with h. corr. 12p, Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Orth, Heinz. "Karl O. Paetel, 1906-1975," dated 30 April 1982. T. with corr. 5p., Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Bibliographies of Paetel's writings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Book lists, Undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Photographs of Paetel, Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Photographs of Paetel acquaintances, Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Stationery items: letterhead, envelopes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Adress Book pages, Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Address labels, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Address, membership lists: P.E.N. Club, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Address lists, press organizations: Deutschsprachiges Forum, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Address lists: Gesprächsfetzen., Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Address lists: Reise ohne Uhrzeit, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Address lists, membership lists: Schutzverband der Schriftsteller deutscher Sprache (SDS), Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Address lists, miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Lists of reviewers, recipients of complimentary copies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1940-1984; 2
  The correspondence files contain approximately 7800 letters in original or photocopy, arranged alphabetically within four sub-series: 1) General correspondence A-Z, 1940-1984; 2) Correspondence in response to Paetel's article in Die Zeit, 1947-1948; 3) Correspondence with publishers and re: publications, 1941-1983; and 4) Correspondence with organizations, institutions, 1941-1981.
  - General Correspondence A-Z, 1940-1984; 2.1
    This section contains the main body of Paetel's correspondence with fellow writers and former youth movement leaders, and includes letters to and from: Stefan Andres, Max Barth, Artur von Behr, Ludwig Blanck-Conrady, Hans Friedrich Blunck, Rudolf Daur, Jean-Pierre des Coudres, Joseph E. Drexel, Charlotte Ehrke, Manfred George, Heinz Gollong, Artur Grosse, Heinz Gruber, Walter Hammer, Pablo Hesslein, Hans Jaeger, Ernst Jnger, Erich von Kahler, Joseph Kaskell, Kurt Kersten, Werner Kindt, Werner Kleinow, Richard Lagrange, Werner Lass, Ernst Niekisch, Heinz Orth, Udo Rukser, Hermann W. Schmid, Albert Theile, Paul Tillich, Max Wehling, Johannes Welke, and Karl August Wittfogel.
    - Abele, Christiana, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Abendroth, Wolfgang, 1949-1970; 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Adorno, Theodor W., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Afenda, Alex, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Agoston, Gerty (Deutscher Presseklub), 1956; Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ahlborn, Knud (Gilde Hoher Meißner), Rundbrief, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Aicher-Scholl, Inge see Scholl, Inge; Geschwister-Scholl-Stiftung, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Albers, Anni, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Albrechtová [Albrecht], Gertrude, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Alexan, Friedrich, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Allen, George, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Anders, Günther, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Anders, Willi, 1944-1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Andres, Stefan, 1940-1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Anton, Georg, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Apel, Hans, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Arendt, Hannah, 1944-1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Arnheim, Rudolf, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Arnold, Heinz Ludwig, 1963-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Auernheimer, Raoul, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Aufhäuser, Siegfried (Council for a Democratic Germany), 1944-1947 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Austerlitz, Robert (Robby), 1962; 1964; 1975; 1977; Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Bab, Julius, 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Baerensprung, H. W., 1944 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Baerwald, Friedrich, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Balabanoff, Angelica, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Baldwin, Roger N, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Bannert, Josef Günther, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Barofsky-Schulz, Sonja, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Baron, Heinrich, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Bartels, Ruth, 1947; 1952 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Barth, Max, 1941-1950 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Bastian, Klaus-Frieder, 1958-1975 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Baum, Vicki, 1942; Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Becker, Käthe, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Beer, Max, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Behr, Artur von, 1948; 1965-1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Behr, Artur von, Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Bek-gran, H, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Benton, José Antonio, 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Berger, Klara (Clara), 1940 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Bergstraesser, Arnold, 1944-1948 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Berlin, Hans, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Berlin, Philipp, 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Bermann-Fischer, Gottfried, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Bernard, R, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Bernholz, Günter, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Bertram, H. G, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Beverstedter, Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Bittner, Franz, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Blanck-Conrady, Ludwig (Bob), 1949; 1962-1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Blank, Herbert, 1946-1949 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Blenk, Hermann, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Blume, Bernhard, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Blunck, Hans Friedrich, 1948-1958 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Boelke, Walter, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Boelte, Emil, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Bondy, Curt, 1944-1970 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Bonhoeffer, Emmi, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Bonnin, Gunther M., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Borch, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Borgese, Elisabeth Mann, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Boveri, Margret, 1957; 1961 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Brandenburg, Hans-Christian, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Brandt, Willy, 1952-1961; 1976 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Brauer, Ernst-Ludwig, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Breuer, Robert, 1945-1947 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Brielmaier, Hugo, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Brneckny, Kurt, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Bruckner, Ferdinand, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Brunner, Karl, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Buchholz, Walther, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Budzislawski, Hermann (Council for a Democratic Germany), 1944 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Buttinger, Joseph, 1944; 1954; 1975 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Canby, Marion, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Canfora, Luciano, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Carossa, Hans, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 32)